Some Live to Climb. They Climb to Live.
Sherpa is a documentary film directed by Jennifer Peedom.
In 2013, the world's media reported on a shocking mountain-high
brawl as European climbers fled a mob of angry Sherpas.
Director Jennifer Peedom and her team set out to uncover the cause of this altercation,
intending to film the 2014 climbing season from the Sherpa's point-of-view.
Instead, they captured Everest's greatest tragedy, when a huge
block of ice crashed down onto the climbing route...
Self, played by Russell Brice.
Self, played by Tim Medvetz.
Self, played by Pasang Tenzing Sherpa.
Self, played by Phurba Tashi Sherpa.
Sherpa is a 2015 documentary film by Australian filmmaker Jennifer Peedom.
It was filmed during the 2014 Mount Everest ice avalanche.
The film explores themes of nepal, natural disaster,
native peoples, woman director, mount everest.